<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AVinCapital</title>
    <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/tags/vn30/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on AVinCapital</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://gswcapital.github.io/tags/vn30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The VN30-Index constituents</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/the-vn30-index-constituents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 17:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/the-vn30-index-constituents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name of Index: VN30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of Index: Price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculation Method: Based on free-float market capitalisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Constituents: 30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feaatures: Contains companies listed on the Ho Chi Minh Exchange with highest market capital and highest liquidity. They normally cover 80% of total market capitalisation and 60% of total market&amp;rsquo;s transaction value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criteria: market capitalisation, free-float, transaction value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Criteria:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not been assigned to be Designated Security, Controlled Security and Under Special Monitoring Segments in 3 months prior to the review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be continuosly listed in at least 6 months. If it&amp;rsquo;s market capitalisation is in top 5, the duration would be 3 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capped: 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review: Halfly (Jan, July). Effected day: the fourth Monday of the month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
2. Review Procedure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market capitalisation&lt;/strong&gt;: All stocks are sorted in terms of 6-month-daily-average market capitalisation in descending order. The top-50 stocks qualify for the selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free-float&lt;/strong&gt;: Those whose free-float is lower than 5% are eliminated from the selection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity&lt;/strong&gt;: The remaining stocks are sorted in term of 6-month average daily traded value in descending.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stocks in Top 20 are selected into index universe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stocks ranked outside the top 40 are eliminated from the index universe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stocks 21th - 40th: The Top 30 are selected into the index universe with high prefer to the existing components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rest of 10 would be considered as the reserved stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the details of the Index, please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Y2mZrlMjDGyIl79ybPVyza-U9h5RonlgTigoOE4eEM4/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;. The exchange rate using is &lt;strong&gt;1USD = 23,000VND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>