<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vo Vinh</title>
    <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vo Vinh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 17:09:49 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gswcapital.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vietnam Daily</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20170217-the-vietnam-dailyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 17:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20170217-the-vietnam-dailyi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The market saw some nice gains today to go along with a few losses for selected bluechips. Market breadth was quite narrow and we saw 28 stocks hit the ceiling while 20 stocks fell to the floor. Foreigners were somewhat less active today with much more selling than buying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markets were mixed with strong gains by banks and real estate &amp;amp; construction. EIB, STB, ROS and CTD all made a positive contribution to the index while VNM, CTG, VCB and GAS all had negative contribution to the index. Though foreigners were active buyers and sellers on VNM today, they ended the day as net sellers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNINDEX: Khả năng năng đi ngang còn kéo dài</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20170209-sideways-nhieu-kha-nang-con-keo-dai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 17:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20170209-sideways-nhieu-kha-nang-con-keo-dai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//c1.staticflickr.com/1/622/32437217920_c15403e72d_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quan sát montly chart của VNINDEX, có thể thấy rằng VNINDEX đã hoàn toàn bứt phá được vùng đỉnh 630 - 650 được thiết lập kể từ 2009; và thậm chí đã vượt mốc 700. Tuy vậy cũng lưu ý rằng mức điểm này không có quá nhiều ý nghĩa về mặt kỹ thuật mà chỉ có đôi chút ý nghĩa về mặt tâm lý con số đơn thuần.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Với những động lực mạnh mẽ đến từ làn sóng niêm yết các doanh nghiệp &amp;ldquo;khủng&amp;rdquo; và hoạt động thoái vốn (có phần) quyết liệt hơn từ phía Chính phủ nhằm mục đích: (1) Nâng cấp thị trường chứng khoán (về số lượng và chất lượng), (2) thu hút vốn đầu tư nước ngoài, (3) phục vụ mục đích thoái vốn ở các doanh nghiệp với giá cao, (4) đem lại dòng tiền chi trả các khoản nợ công đang chiếm tỷ lệ cao đối với GDP; Chính vì vậy VNINDEX được kỳ vọng sẽ còn tiếp tục chinh phục những đỉnh cao&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to open a brokerage account</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/how-to-open-a-brokerage-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 10:48:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/how-to-open-a-brokerage-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Registering a &lt;strong&gt;Securities Trading Code (STC)&lt;/strong&gt;:
Foreign investor (FI) can directly contact to the Vietnam &lt;strong&gt;Securities Depository (VSD)&lt;/strong&gt; to get a trading code. However, it is recommended that FI should contact via a member of VSD (brokerage firms, banks) for more convenience.

The following is required documents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification documents: may be vary depends on type of institution.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual: notarized copy of valid passport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investment Fund: Fund establishment Registration or equivalent documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Institution: Business Registration or equivalent documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open an &lt;strong&gt;Indirect Investment Capital Account (IICA)&lt;/strong&gt;:
FI can contact to the bank which provides the services. It is also high recommended that FI should contact to the broker firms to know which is the most suitable bank. It normally takes 15 - 30 minutes to open an IICA at the bank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open an &lt;strong&gt;Brokerage Account&lt;/strong&gt;:
FI could open trading account at any brokerage firms given the certification of STC. Normally, the brokerage firms where FI(s) open trading account help them to register an STC as well as IICA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be aware of the law of investment as well as related documents which you could find details in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gswcapital.github.io/post/important-legal-documents/&#34;&gt;Important Legal Documents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vietnam Stock Trading Rules</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/vietnam-stock-trading-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 15:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/vietnam-stock-trading-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 2 exchanges in Vietnam, operating on the order-driven basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hsx.vn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOSE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange a.k.a. HSX) was founded in 2000 in HCM city. There are about 324 tickers and their market capital is more or less 1.6 million billion VND (aprox. $70B USD) as of the 15 Feb 2017. Official Website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hsx.vn&#34;&gt;http://www.hsx.vn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hnx.vn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HNX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Ha Noi Stock Exchange) was founded in 2005 in Ha Noi capital. HNX itself has 2 floors: main floor for listed shares, UPCOM floor for unlisted shares (registered). There are 380 tickers listed in HNX (main) and their market capital is about 162 thousand billion VND (aprox. $7B USD) as of the 15 Feb 2017. Also there are 473 tickers listed in UPCOM and there market capital is about 418 thousand billion VND (under $20B USD). Official Website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hnx.vn&#34;&gt;http://www.hnx.vn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three types of securities are being traded in these exchanges: &lt;strong&gt;stock&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;bond&lt;/strong&gt; (state and corporate) and &lt;strong&gt;fund unit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading Hours and Holidays

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOSE and HNX open from Monday to Friday, close on Saturday and Monday and other prestated holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading hours begin at 9:00 to 14:45 with a break from 11:30 to 13:00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are some differences between HOSE and HNX in order matching. While the first and the last 15 minutes of HOSE is for the Open and Close session respectively where the auction-rule will be applied; The HNX is only use the auction-rule for the Close session. The rest of trading hours are use the continuous matching scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please bear in mind that the auction-rule means periodical matching scheme in which orders (LO, ATO) are placed into the order book from 9:00:01 to 9:14:59; the price at which there are largest number of shares matched at 9:15:00 is for the Open price. In case of unmatching, open price would be the previous day&amp;rsquo;s close price. The same is for the last 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The matching scheme is the Price and Time priority&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of Orders

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LO (Limit Order)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATO (At The Open) , ATC (At the Close)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MP (Market Price), MAK (Market And Kill), MOK (Market Or Kill), MTL (Market To Limit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board Lots and Tick Size

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOSE:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 shares per lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The maximum shares per order is 500,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VND10 for price range below VND10,000; VND100 for price range from VND10,000 to VND20,000; VND500 for price range is above 100,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HNX:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100 shares per lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The maximum shares per order is 500,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VND100 for all price range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily Price Limit

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOSE: +/- 7% from reference price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HNX: +/- 10% from reference price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case of common trading day, reference price is the previous day&amp;rsquo;s close price; In case of new listing, the range of 20% will be applied for HOSE and 30% will be applied for HNX based on the prestated reference price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marginal Account and Short Sell

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short Sell is prohibited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Margin trading is only applied for approved stocks which are prestated by HOSE and HNX. Initial Margin is normally 50%. A margin call is issued when the ratio below 90%; and a force to sell is issue when the ratio below 83% or the ratio below 90% in two consecutive days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settlement Cycle

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cylce is T+2. However money come to investor&amp;rsquo;s account in the morning (9:00) while the shares come in the afternoon (16:00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fees and Tax

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum fees trading is set at 0.15% on each transaction value according to the broker firm. The range of fees is 0.15% to 0.40%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other fees (monthly depository fees, lending fees, margin fees) is depended on the broker firms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tax is set at 0.1% on sell transaction value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foreign Trading

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The common FOL is 49% and the available room will be quoted on the priceboard for foreign investor. The room will be automatically updated depended on the buy and sell orders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have question about the trading rules, please do not hesitate to contact me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:votruongvinh@baoviet.com.vn&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;votruongvinh@baoviet.com.vn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:vinh.votruong@gmail.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vinh.votruong@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Drives the Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/what-drives-the-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 15:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/what-drives-the-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following are some &amp;ldquo;hot topics&amp;rdquo;, personally I do think they have large effects on the VN Stock Markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Brexit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Intraday trading (T0) and T+2 short sell.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;SCIC’s divestment&lt;/strong&gt; in biggest listed companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;M&amp;amp;A in VN biggest brand names&lt;/strong&gt; taken by Asia giant corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;FOL – foreign ownership lifting&lt;/strong&gt; in listed companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Government debt.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;FII cash flow&lt;/strong&gt; in/out of VN stock market through ETFs, P-notes &amp;amp; open-ended investment funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;TPP, AEC &amp;amp; FTAs:&lt;/strong&gt; which sectors will get benefit from these trade agreements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;China’s yuan devaluation&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Vietnam’s exchange rate reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Global oil &amp;amp; gas prices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Upgrade VN stock market&lt;/strong&gt; from MSCI’s frontier to emerging market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Banking bad debt &amp;amp; VAMC story.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– &lt;strong&gt;Derivatives market&lt;/strong&gt; starts with index future contract &amp;amp; covered warrant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Legal Dococuments</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/important-legal-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 17:09:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/important-legal-documents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decree 118/2015/ND-CP&lt;/strong&gt; guiding the Law on Investment: Foreign Ownership Limitation (FOL) listed companies are considered as local ones for stock market trading purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circular 123/2015/TT-BTC&lt;/strong&gt; providing specific &amp;amp; detailed documents on the necessary procedures foreign investors must take to operate in the stock exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decree 60/2015/ND-CP&lt;/strong&gt; (replaces Decree 58/2012/ND-CP): provides new regulations on foreign stakes in listed companies, state-own enterprises, bonds&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circular 203/2015/TT-BTC&lt;/strong&gt; guiding transaction activities in which, for the first time investors will be allowed to sell shares which are pending for settlement &amp;amp; make intraday trading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decree 42/2015/ND-CP&lt;/strong&gt; outlines framework on derivative securities &amp;amp; future exchange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20161202-saying-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gswcapital.github.io/post/20161202-saying-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Đã khá lâu rồi không viết lách thứ gì nghiêm túc, chợt thấy cuộc sống cứ bừa bộn, cuống cuồng&amp;hellip; Nhiều điều muốn làm, nhiều điều dang dở&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hay là mình lại viết, viết một cái gì đó, ít ra là viết, thậm chí chỉ là viết ra những con chữ?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>